Guide to the Gertrude White Papers 1916-1917
Montana State University-Bozeman Library
Gertrude White Papers
1916-1917
Montana State University-Bozeman Library, Merrill G Burlingame Special Collections P.O. Box 173320 Bozeman, MT 59717-3320 United States Phone (406) 994-4242 Fax (406) 994-2851 http://www.lib.montana.edu/archives/ University Archivist spcoll@www.lib.montana.edu
Collection 1421, MtBC, us
White, Gertrude
1 folder
The Gertrude White papers includes original handwritten letters, envelopes, and billing statements for Mrs. Gertrude White. Correspondents include: Mrs. J.L. Guthrie, Lester White, and Roxana Beck of Montana Deaconess School. Topics discussed include: an expected delivery, Lester’s daily activities at the children’s home, and finances. Locations in Montana include Bozeman, Manhattan, and Helena.
Biographical Note
Frances Gertrude White was born on July 24, 1881 in Willow Creek, Montana, as the daughter of a merchant. In July of 1901 Gertrude married Walter White; two years later their son Lester Roland White was born. Four years after Lester's birth, Walter and Gertrude were divorced. In 1910 she lived with her son Lester in Bozeman, Montana where she worked as dressmaker out of her home. During 1914-1922 Gertrude was a nurse and a midwife. Ten years later, she began working at Goy Good Store as a sales lady. She passed away on April 26 1965 and was buried in the Meadowview Cemetery in Manhattan, Montana.
The Gertrude White papers, 1916-1917 includes original handwritten letters, envelopes, and billing statements for Mrs. Gertrude White. The three handwritten letters in this collection include: one from a Mrs. J.L. Guthrie stating that she was expected to go into labor between March 2nd and the 12th in 1917 and she wanted Mrs. Gertrude to come and help with the delivery. This letter was dated February 2, 1917 in Manhattan, Montana. Then the second letter is from Lester White to his mother, Gertrude. The letter is dated February 18,1917 in Helena, Montana. The letter describes Lester's daily activities while at the children’s home in Helena Montana. Then the third letter is from Roxana Beck, Principle of Montana Deaconess School during 1917. Written on February 28, the letter informs Gertrude how Lester was doing and provides her with a billing statement in regard to Lester. The collection also includes multiple billing statements ranging from a shoe store to a statement from the children's home Lester was residing at and envelopes that either correspond with the letters or billing statements or were just kept by Gertrude.
This collection is open for research.
Original letters, billing statements, and envelopes sent to, and kept by Mrs. Gertrude White of Bozeman, Montana, were donated by the Museum of the Rockies of Bozeman, Montana to Montana State University Library March 1985.
Children and Youth; Elementary and Secondary Education; Economics and Banking; Medicine and Health; Women; Montana; Bozeman
- Reed's Bootery (Box-folder 1/1)
  Sales receipt for Mrs. Walter White
- Phillips Book Store (Box-folder 1/2)
  Envelope
- Guthrie, J.L., Mrs., February 2, 1917 (Box-folder 1/3)
  Letter to Gertrude White February 2, 1917
- Guthrie, J.L., Mrs. (Box-folder 1/4)
- Envelope, 1917 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Phillips, S.G., Dr., 1916 (Box-folder 1/6)
  Billing statement addressed to Gertrude White, 1916
- White, Lester, February 18, 1917 (Box-folder 1/7)
  Letter to Gertrude White February 18, 1917
- Chambers-Fisher Company (Box-folder 1/8)
- Chambers-Fisher Company, 1917 (Box-folder 1/9)
  Billing Statement addressed to Gertrude White, 1917
- Montana Deaconess School (Box-folder 1/10)
- Montana Deaconess School, 1917 (Box-folder 1/11)
  Billing statement addressed to Gertrude White, 1917
- Beck, Roxana, February 28, 1917 (Box-folder 1/12)
  Letter to Gertrude White February 28, 1917